spreaker.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy

Spreaker collects some Personal Data from its Users.

## Owner and Data Controller

Voxnest, Inc  
195 Montague Street, 11th Floor  
Brooklyn, NY, 11201 

**Owner contact email:** [info@voxnest.com](mailto:info@voxnest.com)

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that Spreaker collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: first name, email address, Cookies and Usage Data.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using Spreaker.  
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by Spreaker is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for Spreaker to provide its services. In cases where Spreaker specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by Spreaker or by the owners of third-party services used by Spreaker serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through Spreaker and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of Spreaker (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

  * Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;
  * provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
  * processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
  * processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
  * processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract. 

### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.

Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve transferring the User's Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.

### Retention time

Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.

Therefore:

  * Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
  * Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.

Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

## The purposes of processing

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes: Registration and authentication, Access to third-party accounts, Handling payments, Analytics, Contacting the User, Advertising, Remarketing and behavioral targeting and Hosting and backend infrastructure.

Users can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.

## Facebook permissions asked by Spreaker

Spreaker may ask for some Facebook permissions allowing it to perform actions with the User's Facebook account and to retrieve information, including Personal Data, from it. This service allows Spreaker to connect with the User's account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook, Inc.

For more information about the following permissions, refer to the [Facebook permissions documentation](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/authentication/permissions/) and to the [Facebook privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

The permissions asked are the following:

### Basic information

By default, this includes certain User’s Data such as id, name, picture, gender, and their locale. Certain connections of the User, such as the Friends, are also available. If the User has made more of their Data public, more information will be available.

### Email

Provides access to the User's primary email address.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

This type of service allows Spreaker to access Data from your account on a third-party service and perform actions with it.  
These services are not activated automatically, but require explicit authorization by the User.

#### Facebook account access (Spreaker)

This service allows Spreaker to connect with the User's account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook, Inc.

Permissions asked: Email.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php). Privacy Shield participant.

#### Twitter account access (Twitter, Inc.)

This service allows Spreaker to connect with the User's account on the Twitter social network, provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant. 

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on Spreaker, possibly based on User interests.  
This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below. Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside Spreaker. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

#### DoubleClick for Publishers (Google, Inc.)

DoubleClick for Publishers is an advertising service provided by Google, Inc. that allows the Owner to run advertising campaigns in conjunction with external advertising networks that the Owner, unless otherwise specified in this document, has no direct relationship with. In order to opt out from being tracked by various advertising networks, Users may make use of [Youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). In order to understand Google's use of data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).  
This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of Spreaker and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.  
Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: [www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en).

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/).

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google, Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of Spreaker, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Privacy Shield participant.

#### Mailing list or newsletter (Spreaker)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning Spreaker. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to Spreaker or after making a purchase.

Personal Data collected: email address.

#### Unbounce (Unbounce Marketing Solutions, Inc.)

Unbounce is a service that helps us showing landing pages to our user and let the users ask us to get in touch with them. By registering on our landing pages, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing commercial or promotional nature concerning Spreaker.

Place of processing: United States or other countries outside of where you live for the purposes as described in the following policies – [Privacy Policy](https://unbounce.com/privacy/).

Payment processing services enable Spreaker to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, Spreaker shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.  
Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

#### PayPal (PayPal, Inc.)

PayPal is a payment service provided by PayPal, Inc., which allows Users to make online payments.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: See the PayPal privacy policy – [Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/privacy). 

#### Stripe (Stripe, Inc)

Stripe is a payment service provided by Stripe, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/terms/US). Privacy Shield participant. 

This type of service has the purpose of hosting Data and files that enable Spreaker to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of Spreaker. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

#### Amazon Web Services (AWS) (Amazon Web Services, Inc.)

Amazon Web Services is a hosting and backend service provided by Amazon.com, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

#### Cloudinary (Cloudinary Ltd.)

Cloudinary is a hosting service provided by Cloudinary Ltd.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: Israel – [Privacy Policy](https://cloudinary.com/privacy).

By registering or authenticating, Users allow Spreaker to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, Spreaker will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.

#### Direct registration (Spreaker)

The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to Spreaker.

Personal Data collected: email address and first name.

#### Facebook Authentication (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Authentication is a registration and authentication service provided by Facebook, Inc. and is connected to the Facebook social network.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/help/405977429438260).Privacy Shield participant.

#### Twitter OAuth (Twitter, Inc.)

Twitter Oauth is a registration and authentication service provided by Twitter, Inc. and is connected to the Twitter social network.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://dev.twitter.com/terms/api-terms). Privacy Shield participant.

#### Google OAuth (Google, Inc.)

Google OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Google, Inc. and is connected to the Google network.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

This type of service allows Spreaker and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of Spreaker by the User.  
This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

#### AdWords Remarketing (Google, Inc.)

AdWords Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google, Inc. that connects the activity of Spreaker with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout).

#### Facebook Pixel and Custom Audience (Facebook, Inc. and Facebook Ireland Ltd.)

Facebook is a social network and an advertising service provided by Facebook, Inc. and Facebook Ireland Ltd.

Place of processing: United States or other countries outside of where you live for the purposes as described in the following policies – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Cookie Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/).

## Further information about Personal Data

ElasticMail is an email address management and message sending service provided by Elastic Mail, Inc.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://elasticemail.com/resources/usage-policies/privacy-policy).

AdsWizz is a digital audio and video advertising service provided by AdsWizz, Inc.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.adswizz.com/our-privacy-policy/).

TargetSpot is a digital audio and video advertising service provided by TargetSpot, Inc. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.targetspot.com/en/privacy-policy/).

Triton Digital is a digital audio and video advertising service provided by Triton Digital, Inc. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.tritondigital.com/privacy-policy).

TenderApp is a support and contact request management service provided by Once Upon A Time Productions, LLC., or "ENTP". 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://tenderapp.com/privacy/).

User can send invitations or any other type of communications related to any UGC created within Spreaker by using external social networks already installed in the devices (e.g. Facebook, Youtube, Twich etc.). In these cases, User must be aware that the Data are processed by such third parties according to their privacy policy and without any possibility for the Owner to exercise any kind of control over the further processing of the Data shared by the User. 

Please be aware that other users of Spreaker might re-post or otherwise share what you post, which could include Data such as your name, nickname/screen-name, video and other information about you, as well as information about content that you post. These other users might make such information publicly available. The Owner processes the Data to enable the display on Spreaker and sharing of such information through Spreaker by other users. 

This Service is not intended for use by children, especially those under age 13. No one under age 13 is allowed to register for the Service or provide any personally identifiable information or use our social, community and public discussion areas, photo and video galleries, chats, and elsewhere. Minors between the ages of 13 and 17, inclusive, must get the permission of their parent(s) or legal guardian(s) before using the Service. If your children disclose information about themselves in publicly accessible areas of the Service, they may get unsolicited messages from other parties. Accordingly, you should tell them not to do so. If you're worried about your children's activities or their privacy on the Service, we encourage you to contact us at the contact details available at the beginning of this document.

California’s "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers asking about the business' practices related to disclosing personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If you wish to opt-out of our sharing of your information with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes or to find out more about your opt-out rights, please contact our Data Controller as described above.

Spreaker may send push notifications to the User.

## The rights of Users

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following:

  * **Withdraw their consent at any time.** Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
  * **Object to processing of their Data.** Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
  * **Access their Data.** Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
  * **Verify and seek rectification.** Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
  * **Restrict the processing of their Data.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it. 
  * **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
  * **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.** Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User's consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
  * **Lodge a complaint.** Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

### Details about the right to object to processing

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document. 

### How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

## Cookie Policy

Spreaker uses Cookies. To learn more and for a detailed cookie notice, the User may consult the [Cookie Policy](https://www.spreaker.com/cookies)

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of Spreaker or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. 

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, Spreaker may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request. 

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, Spreaker and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with Spreaker (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose. 

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document. 

### How “Do Not Track” requests are handled

Spreaker does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page and possibly within Spreaker and/or - as far as technically and legally feasible - sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. 

Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required. 

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically through Spreaker (or third-party services employed in Spreaker), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use Spreaker, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using Spreaker who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

#### Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of Spreaker. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of Spreaker.

#### Spreaker (or this Application)

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

#### Service

The service provided by Spreaker as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

#### European Union (or EU)

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

#### User Generated Content (or UGC)

Means any information and material displayed by you on Spreaker and/or any other part of the Services, but excluding the links to third-party sites, apps, addresses or phone numbers and the content provided by the Owner.

#### Cookies

Small sets of data stored in the User's device.

* * *

#### Legal information

This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).

This privacy policy relates solely to Spreaker, if not stated otherwise within this document.
